Guide to the Henry Lewis Stimson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Memoranda, Minutes of Meetings, Series II
  - Correspondence re: corrections in the testimony of H. L. S. to the Army- Pearl Harbor Board (2, 2a, 2b) (Box 173, Folder 3)
  - List of questions received from the Army Pearl Harbor Board (3) (Box 173, Folder 4)
  - Drafts of H. L. S.'s opening statement to the Army Pearl Harbor Board (3a, 3b) (Box 173, Folder 5)
  - Trial brief for use in testimony to Army Pearl Harbor Board ( 3c) (Box 173, Folder 6)
  - Answers to questions 2, 7, and 10-16 of the Army Pearl Harbor Board (Box 173, Folder 7)
  - Answers to questions 1-16 of the- Army Pearl Harbor Board list (3e) (Box 173, Folder 8)
  - Notes from H. L. S. diary for use in testimony before the Army Pearl Harbor Bonrd (4, 4a) (Box 173, Folder 9)
  - Important Arrmy, Navy and other U. S. communications (5) (Box 173, Folder 10)
  - Important papers referred to in H. L. S. testimony to Army Pearl Harbor Board (5a) (Box 173, Folder 11)
  - Information available to the commanding general of the Hawaiian dept. (5b) (Box 173, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence re: Pearl Harbor radar problems (6, 6a, 6b, 6c, 6d) (Box 173, Folder 13)
  - Memoranda re: H. L. S. appointments and Cordell Hull appointments before Dec 7, 1941 (7, 7a) (Box 173, Folder 14)
  - Summaries of messages to Admiral Kimmel, Admiral Stark prior to Dec 7, 1941 (8, 8a) (Box 173, Folder 15)
  - Secretary Hull IS statement re: Nov 25 and 28 meetings (9); copies of correspondence: Thomas North and H. L. S. (10, 10a) (Box 173, Folder 16)
  - Attack upon Pearl Harbor: Roberts Board report (11); H. L. S. revision of message to Short, 11/27/1941 (Box 173, Folder 17)
- Speeches, Writings, Statements, 1888-1975; Series III
  - Speeches
    - Sir Henry Vane the Younger, the Deforest Prize Oration, 1888 (Box 174, Folder 1)
    - 1900-1908 (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - 1910 April 15 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - Harvard Lectures, 1910 May 5-6 (Box 174, Folder 4)
    - Acceptance speech of Republican candidate for Governor of New York at the Republican Club, 1910 October 4 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - Opening speech in the campaign for Governor of New York State at Columbia University, 1910 October 12 (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - Carnegie Hall-speech, notes, outlines, 1910 October 14 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - Notes for speeches in campaign for Governor of New York, dates and identified by place, 1910 October 17-November 4 (Box 174, Folder 8)
    - Three volumes, 1910 (Box 175)
    - One volume, 1910 (Box 176)
    - Unidentified campaign speeches, 1910 October-November (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified notes for speeches in New York Gubernatorial campaign, 1910 September-November (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - Copies of speeches, extracts, and fragments duplicated in bound volumes of speeches, 1910 October-November (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - Speech at dinner for Governor Dix at Lotus Club, 1911 January (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - "Some Phases of the Progressive Movement in the Republican Party," delivered at the McKinley Banquet, Cleveland, Ohio, 1911 January 18 (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - "National Control and the Public Welfare," delivered at Congress of National Federation of Religious Liberals at Cooper Union, 1911 April 27 (Box 177, Folder 6)
    - The proposed reciprocity agreement with Canada delivered before the Intercolonial Club in Boston, 1911 May 24 (Box 177, Folder 7)
    - Address to the graduating class of the U.S. Military Academy, 1911 June 13 (Box 177, Folder 8)
    - Undated speech notes, [1911 Jun] (Box 177, Folder 9)
    - Four speeches made on Caribbean trip to Adjuntos, Arecibo, Ponce, and Havana, 1911 July-August (Box 177, Folder 10)
    - Speech in presentation of the Secretary of War Cup to Percival Dewitt Gibson in Washington, DC, 1911 November 2 (Box 177, Folder 11)
    - "Some Problems of the Panama Canal" before the Commercial Club at Kansas City, Missouri, 1911 November 14 (Box 177, Folder 12)
    - Address at the Republican Club, New York City, 1911 December 15 (Box 177, Folder 13)
    - Notes for speech at conference in Philadelphia regarding the Panama Canal, 1912 January 27 (Box 177, Folder 14)
    - "The Progressive Character of President Taft's Administration" before the Taft Club, Chicago, Illinois, 1912 March 5 (Box 177, Folder 15)
    - "The Army" before the West Point Alumni, Washington, DC, 1912 March 30 (Box 177, Folder 16)
    - Campaign speech for the nomination of Taft, 1912 [April or May ?] (Box 177, Folder 17)
    - Major Butt, The Soldier, Washington, DC, 1912 May 5 (Box 177, Folder 18)
    - Statement to Political Science class, University of Pennsylvania, 1912 May 16 (Box 177, Folder 19)
    - Statement to press, 1912 May 27 (Box 177, Folder 19)
    - Address before the National Conservation Congress at Indianapolis, Indiana, 1912 October 1 (Box 177, Folder 20)
    - Taft campaign speech, Buffalo, NY, 1912 October 16 (Box 177, Folder 21)
    - Taft campaign speech, St. Paul, Minnesota, 1912 October 23 (Box 177, Folder 21)
    - "Initiative and Responsibility of the Executive for Inefficient Legislation," before the Law Academy of Philadelphia, 1913 May 27 (Box 177, Folder 22)
    - Outlines for speech before the Law Academy of Philadelphia, 1913 May 27 (Box 177, Folder 23)
    - Notes and others material used in preparation for the speech before the Law Academy of Philadelphia (Box 177, Folder 24)
    - Two printed copies of the May 27, 1913 speech before the Law Academy of Philadelphia (Box 177, Folder 25)
    - Notes for address to Yale Alumni meeting, 1913 June 17 (Box 177, Folder 26)
    - Speech at Cooper Union, New York City at notification to nominees of fusion ticket, 1913 October (Box 177, Folder 27)
    - Founders Day speech, Phillips Academy, Andover, Massachusetts, 1913 October 11 (Box 177, Folder 28)
    - Two sets of unidentified speech notes, [1913-1917?] (Box 177, Folder 29)
    - "Republican Issues," before the Manhattan Republican Club, 1914 February 4 (Box 177, Folder 30)
    - Lincoln's Birthday speech at Republican Banquet, Utica, New York (Box 177, Folder 31)
    - Notes for speech to George W. Curtis Club, Staten Island, New York (Box 177, Folder 32)
    - Notes for Duland's speech, 1914 October 26 (Box 177, Folder 33)
    - "The Principle of Reponsibility in Government," an address at the dinner meeting of the Academy of Political Science, New York City, 1914 November 19 (Box 177, Folder 34)
    - "National Defense: A Problem for Businessmen," address at Peace Insurance meeting of Merchants Association of New York, 1914 December 1 (Box 177, Folder 35)
    - Notes for speech to Young Republican Club, 1915 January 8 (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - Remarks before the Rochester, New York City Club regarding National Defense, 1915 January 23 (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - Notes for speech to Aldine Club on subject of Political Reform, 1915 January 26 (Box 178, Folder 3)
    - Remarks as presiding officer at Civic Forum discussion of National Defense, 1915 February 3 (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - Notes for speech on National Defense at St. Ursula, 1915 March 9 (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - Notes for speech on National Defense at Labor Temple, 1915 March 17 (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - Notes for speech on National Defense at Brooklyn University Club, 1915 March 30 (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - Speech and speech notes for Harvard Law School Association, 1915 April 1 (Box 178, Folder 6)
    - Notes for speech at J.C. Walters Post, Grand Army of the Republic (GAR), 1915 May 31 (Box 178, Folder 7)
    - Speech to Young Republicans Club of Brooklyn on Constitutional Convention and Responsible Government, 1915 June 4 (Box 178, Folder 8)
    - "The Duty of Preparedness Today," before the National Security League at Carnegie Hall, 1915 June 14 (Box 178, Folder 9)
    - Notes for several speeches in campaign for ratification of new state constitution, 1915 October (Box 178, Folder 10)
    - Undated notes for speeches in campaign for ratification of new state constitution, [1915 September-Oct] (Box 178, Folder 11)
    - Speech notes and fragments--untitled and undated on subject of National Defense and Preparedness, [1915?] (Box 178, Folder 12)
    - Notes for speech to Cosmopolitan Club on subject of Military Preparedness, 1916 January 5 (Box 178, Folder 13)
    - Remarks at annual dinner of the New York State Bar Association in honor of Elihu Root, 1916 January 15 (Box 178, Folder 14)
    - Remarks at the National Security Congress, Washington, DC, 1916 January 22 (Box 178, Folder 15)
    - Notes for speech on Preparedness and National Defense, New Rochelle, New York, 1916 January 30 (Box 178, Folder 16)
    - Notes for speeches on Preparedness and National Defense, Plattsburgh, New York, 1916 March 20, 1916 undated (Box 178, Folder 16)
    - Notes for speech at Andover Alumni Banquet, 1916 April 17 (Box 178, Folder 17)
    - Notes for speeches in election campaign, 1916 September-November (Box 178, Folder 18)
    - "Some Reflections upon our Military Experiment of 1916" delivered at the Congress of Constructive Patriotism, Washington, DC, 1917 January 25 (Box 178, Folder 19)
    - Speech at New Haven, Connecticut, regarding National Defense and Military Training, 1917 February 27 (Box 178, Folder 20)
    - Draft and reference material for a speech (which was not given) for Harvard Law School Centennial, 1917 spring (Box 178, Folder 21)
    - Speech notes regarding War and Defense, New York University, 3 sets, 1917 March 21-circa April (Box 178, Folder 22)
    - "The Issues of the War," speech delivered on Western trip and notes, 1917 April 1-15 (Box 178, Folder 23)
    - Remarks at the Memorial Meeting for Theodore Roosevelt at the Harvard Club, 1919 February 9 (Box 178, Folder 24)
    - Unidentified speech notes regarding the War and the League of Nations, 1919 March 21 (Box 178, Folder 25)
    - Notes for speech on Army Relief Service, 1919 April 30 (Box 178, Folder 26)
    - Two drafts of remarks at the presentation of the John Fritz Medal to Major General Goethals by the Civic Forum, 1919 May 22 (Box 178, Folder 27)
    - Notes and memoranda for Roosevelt speech at dinner of Nassau County Republican Club, Garden City, New York, 1919 October 27 (Box 178, Folder 28)
    - Notes for speech to Carry on Association, 1919 (Box 178, Folder 29)
    - "Yale in the Great War," delivered in Woolsey Hall at the dedication of Memorial Tablets, 1920 November 21 (Box 178, Folder 30)
    - Address to the meeting of the National Coal Association in Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1923 June 20 (Box 178, Folder 31)
    - Press summary and outline for address delivered at the Forum, Philadelphia regarding The American Peace Award, 1924 February 4 (Box 178, Folder 32)
    - Address at the Inner Temple, Edinburgh, Scotland, during the meeting of the Canadian and American Bar: speech, outline, and memorandum, 1924 July (Box 178, Folder 33)
    - Speech at the Union League Club on Army Day, 1924 December 4 (Box 178, Folder 34)
    - "Public Utilities," address at National Republican Club, 1925 January 24 (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - Outline and notes for speech to National Republican Club, 1925 January 24 (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - Reference material for "Public Operation vs. Private Operation of Public Utilities" regarding Cleveland from Newton D. Baker, 1925 January 24 (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - Reference material for National Republican Club speech regarding Ontario and Sir Adam Beck, 1925 January 24 (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Reference material for National Republican Club speech regarding Robert Howell and Nebraska, 1925 January 24 (Box 179, Folder 5)
    - Other reference material for debate at National Republican Club, 1925 January 24 (Box 179, Folder 6-7)
    - Printed copies and press summary of speech at National Republican Club, 1925 January 24 (Box 179, Folder 8)
    - Remarks at the dinner of the Academy of Political Science, New York City, 1925 March 9 (Box 179, Folder 9)
    - "Citizens' Military Training in Relation to Militarism and the World Court," outline for remarks at debate at National Collegiate World Court Conference (Box 179, Folder 10)
    - Remarks at the New York County Republican meeting in memory of Herbert Parsons, 1926 winter (Box 179, Folder 11)
    - Notes for speech to Episcopal group regarding the Philippines, 1926 November 18 (Box 179, Folder 12)
    - Remarks made at a dinner given for General Summerall, 1926 November 19 (Box 179, Folder 13)
    - Transcript of dinner meeting of the Council on Foreign Relations at which Henry Lewis Stimson gave an address regarding the Philippines. Also, outline for this talk., 1926 December 14 (Box 179, Folder 14)
    - Remarks at the reunion dinner of the Delegates to the New York Constitutional Convention of 1915, 1926 December 17 (Box 179, Folder 15)
    - Address delivered at Syracuse University, 1927 June 13 (Box 179, Folder 16)
    - Remarks at the presentation of Julius M. Mayer portrait. Reference material includes a memorial from the New York County Lawyers Association, possibly also written by Henry Lewis Stimson, 1927 November 14 (Box 179, Folder 17)
    - Remarks at the luncheon of the San Francisco sector of the Association of the Army, 1928 February 2 (Box 179, Folder 18)
    - Inaugural address of the Governor General delivered on the new Luneta, printed copy only, 1928 March 1 (Box 179, Folder 19)
    - Message of the Governor General to the Eighth Philippine Legislature at the opening of the first session, printed copy only, 1928 July 16 (Box 179, Folder 20)
    - Remarks on the first anniversary of the death of Leonard Wood, 1928 August 7 (Box 179, Folder 21)
    - Address before the meeting of the American Chamber of Commerce in Manila, 1928 August 15 (Box 179, Folder 22)
    - Regarding governmental policy and the general conditions in the Philippines, 1928 September 27 (Box 179, Folder 23)
    - Notes for speech before the Philippine Medical Association, 1928 December 12 (Box 179, Folder 24)
    - Speech before the Businessmen's Convention, Manila, 1929 February 6 (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - Farewell addresss before special session of the Philippine Legislature, 1929 February 9 (Box 180, Folder 2)
    - Addresss to Philippine Legislature, 1929 February 11 (Box 180, Folder 3)
    - London Naval Conference
      - Memorandum for speech on American needs for second plenary session of the London Naval Conference (not used), 1930 January (Box 180, Folder 4)
      - Speech delivered at the opening session of the London Naval Conference, 1930 January 21 (Box 180, Folder 5)
      - Address to the radio audience in Great Britain and the United States regarding the London Naval Conference, 1930 January 28 (Box 180, Folder 6)
      - Radio address regarding the London Naval Conference, 1930 April 13 (Box 180, Folder 7)
      - Radio address made from London to the Associated Press luncheon regarding the London Naval Conference (Box 180, Folder 8)
      - Address at the final plenary session of the London Naval Conference, 1930 April 21 (Box 180, Folder 9)
      - Remarks at the city reception, New York City, on return from London Naval Conference, speech and draft, 1930 April 29 (Box 180, Folder 10)
      - Radio remarks to the school children of America regarding the London Naval Treatry, 1930 May 15 (Box 180, Folder 11)
    - Remarks at a luncheon honoring President-elect of Colombia Enrique Olaya at the Pan American Union, 1930 June 5 (Box 180, Folder 12)
    - Radio address in connection with the unveiling of the Peace Monument in Toronto, Canada on the occasion of the meeting of the Imperial Council of the Shrine, 1930 June 12 (Box 180, Folder 13)
    - Radio speech regarding ratification of the London Naval Treaty, 1930 June 12 (Box 180, Folder 14)
    - Remarks in honor of President-elect of Brazil Dr. Julio Prestes at a special session of the Governing Board of the Pan American Union, 1930 June 13 (Box 180, Folder 15)
    - Address to the Republican State Convention, Albany, New York, 1930 September 25 (Box 180, Folder 16)
    - Welcome address to the Sixth Congress of the Permanent International Association of Road Congresses, 1930 October 6 (Box 180, Folder 17)
    - Radio address regarding the candidacy of Charles H. Tuttle for the office of Governor of New York State, 1930 October 28 (Box 180, Folder 18)
    - Speech at Armistice Ball, Mayflower Hotel, 1930 November 11 (Box 180, Folder 19)
    - Remarks on centenary of Bolivar's death at Pan American Union, a copy from the Pan American Bulletin only, [1930 Dec?] (Box 180, Folder 20)
    - Address before the officers of the Army War College, draft and revised copy, 1931 January 5 (Box 180, Folder 21)
    - Second copy and stenographic notes of Army War College speech, 1931 January 5 (Box 180, Folder 22)
    - Remarks at the opening of the first Baltimore Pan-American Exhibition at the Baltimore Museum of Art, speech and draft, 1931 January 15 (Box 180, Folder 23)
    - "The United States and Other American Republics," before the Council on Foreign Relations, New York City, 1931 February 6 (Box 180, Folder 24)
    - Outlines and drafts for Council on Foreign Relations speech, 1931 February 6 (Box 180, Folder 25)
    - Remarks on the occasion of the retirement of the Brazilian Ambassador at the Pan American Union, drafted by J. Rowe, 1931 March 23 (Box 180, Folder 26)
    - Two drafts of an undelivered speech regarding the results of the London Naval Conference, referred to in Pierre de L. Boals' letter, Mar 24, 1931 (Box 180, Folder 27)
    - Address on the celebration of Pan American Day to the Governing Board of the Pan American Union, 1931 April 14 (Box 180, Folder 28)
    - Greetings to the Japanese People on the radio on the occasion of the Emperor's birthday, 1931 April 29 (Box 180, Folder 29)
    - Remarks in introducing General Edward Higgins of the Salvation Army at Constitution Hall, draft and reference materials, 1931 May 8 (Box 180, Folder 30)
    - Radio address on the Cabinet Hour regarding the work of the State Department, 1931 May 9 (Box 180, Folder 31)
    - Notes for remarks at the unveiling of the Titanic memorial, 1931 May 26 (Box 180, Folder 32)
    - Remarks on receiving an honorary degree at Pennsylvania Military College, Chester, Pennsylvania, citation included, 1931 June 9 (Box 180, Folder 33)
    - Remarks for a scheduled radio broadcast regarding reparations (cancelled), 1931 June 23 (Box 180, Folder 34)
    - Remarks at the opening of the fourth Pan American Commercial Conference, 1931 October 5 (Box 180, Folder 35)
    - Draft of remarks for appearance at the opening of the George Washington Bridge (cancelled), 1931 October 24 (Box 180, Folder 36)
    - Remarks at a luncheon of the Pan American Union honoring the retiring Minister of Ecuador, Homero Viteri Lafronte, 1931 November 30 (Box 180, Folder 37)
    - Message of acceptance of bust of George Washington by Pan American Union, read by Under-Secretary Castle, 1932 February 22 (Box 181, Folder 1)
    - Rough draft--noted as appropriate for domestic use before some body such as the Foreign Trade Council, [1932 winter-spring?] (Box 181, Folder 2)
    - "America's Actual and Possible Contributions towards the Implementations of the Kellogg Pact," drafts for a projected speech, 1932 May (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - "America's position in the Disarmament Conference and its Contribution towards its Work," draft speech made on board the Vulcania on return from the Geneva Conference, 1932 May (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - Unused remarks for farewell luncheon of the Pan American Union for the Ambassador of Cuba, Orestes Ferrara, 1932 May 20 (Box 181, Folder 5)
    - "The Position of the Republican Party on the Eighteenth Amendment," radio address, 1932 June 16 (Box 181, Folder 6)
    - Radio address to the People of Canada on Dominion Day, file includes 3 drafts for speech submitted by others, 1932 July 1 (Box 181, Folder 7)
    - "The Pact of Paris: Three Years of Development" before the Council on Foreign Relations, New York City
      - Reading copy with notes by E. Regnier, 1932 August 8 (Box 181, Folder 8)
      - First outline, analysis, draft and revisions, 1932 August 8 (Box 181, Folder 9-10)
      - Third draft, returned copy with Herbert Hoover's annotations, revisions after Hoover's comments, and Hoover's letter about the revisions, 1932 August 8 (Box 181, Folder 11)
      - Fourth draft and revisions, 1932 August 8 (Box 181, Folder 12)
      - Jul 30 copy from E. Regnier with letter of suggestions and revisions of the draft, 1932 August 8 (Box 181, Folder 13)
      - Copy of Aug 3 with letter from E. Regnier with suggestions, 1932 August 8 (Box 181, Folder 14)
      - Notes and unidentified drafts, 1932 August 8 (Box 181, Folder 15)
    - Remarks by Henry Lewis Stimson at a luncheon of the Pan American Union tendered to the retiring Minister of Bolivia, Luis O. Abell, 1932 September 27 (Box 181, Folder 16)
    - "Mr. Hoover's Foreign Policy and the Commercial Welfare of the United States," delivered at the Union League Club of Philadelphia, 1932 October 1 (Box 181, Folder 17)
    - Speech notes for Presidential campaign, "Hoover and the Common Man", 1932 October 11 (Box 181, Folder 18)
    - Speech notes for Presidential campaign "The Record of the Administration for Peace," Pittsburgh speech, 1932 October 11 (Box 181, Folder 18)
    - Address to the National Republican Club, New York City, 1932 October 18 (Box 181, Folder 19)
    - "The Work of the United States Government in the Promotion of Peace During the Past Three Years," before the Council of the Methodist Episcopal Church for the Pittsburgh Area, at Pittsburgh, 1932 October 26 (Box 181, Folder 20)
    - "The Republican Proposal as to the Eighteenth Amendment--A Step Forward, Not Backward" at the University Club, Washington, DC, 1932 October 29 (Box 181, Folder 21)
    - "Summing up the Campaign," radio address from Memorial Hall in Dayton, Ohio, 1932 November 2 (Box 181, Folder 22)
    - Remarks at the Pan American Union Farewell Luncheon for the Retiring Ambassador of Chile, Miguel Cruchaga Tocornal, 1932 November 30 (Box 181, Folder 23)
    - Speech on Presentation of Medal to Elihu Root, [1933?] (Box 181, Folder 24)
    - Remarks to the Governing Board of the Pan American Union, 1933 February 20 (Box 181, Folder 25)
    - Remarks on Inauguration of Radio and Telephone Service between United States and Panama, 1933 February 24 (Box 181, Folder 25)
    - Remarks to American Foreign Service Association, Washington, 1933 February 28 (Box 181, Folder 25)
    - Notes for talk at Skull and Bones Meeting, New Haven, Connecticut, 1933 June (Box 181, Folder 26)
    - Princeton University, Stafford Little Foundation, "Democracy and Nationalism in Europe," first to fourth lectures, 1934 April 9-12 (Box 181, Folder 27-30)
    - Memoranda of conversations used in preparation of Princeton lectures, "Democracy and Nationalism in Europe", 1934 April (Box 181, Folder 31)
    - Notes on reading done for Princeton lectures on "Democracy and Nationalism in Europe" (Box 181, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous notes used in preparation of the Princeton lectures on "Democracy and Nationalism in Europe", 1934 April (Box 181, Folder 33)
    - Footnotes, appendix, and other materials used in the published version of the Princeton lectures, "Democracy and Nationalism in Europe", 1934 April (Box 181, Folder 34)
    - Mailing list for Democracy and Nationalism in Europe, 1934 (Box 181, Folder 35)
    - "America Must Trade Abroad to Preserve Her Welfare and Character," radio address under the auspices of the Intercollegiate Council on International Cooperation, 1934 April 29 (Box 181, Folder 36)
    - Notes used in talk to Intercollegiate Young Alumni at the Town Hall Club regarding Internationalism (Box 181, Folder 37)